<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Charlie Brumbaugh's Blog</title><description>Outdoor Adventures and Programming</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Charlie Brumbaugh's Blog</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.19</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 03:45:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day of the climb, I woke up really early and headed up the mountain. It was hard going with lots of talus and rubble. I made it up to the final lake and then headed straight up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, I missed the right-hand turn to the second bowl&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/failed-attemp-on-mt-ritter-the-climb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3bf590b850b00e1e8d304d</guid><category>Mt. Ritter</category><category>Peak Ascents</category><category>2014</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 02:38:28 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0691.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0691.JPG" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day of the climb, I woke up really early and headed up the mountain. It was hard going with lots of talus and rubble. I made it up to the final lake and then headed straight up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, I missed the right-hand turn to the second bowl and headed straight on pass it. It turned out that the rocks were too steep and after I knocked a basketball sized rock loose and it rolled and rolled and rolled, I decided to take some pictures and head down. It was only 7:03 in the morning when I decided to quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0680.JPG" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I headed back down the mountain, pausing to take this picture of the Ritter Lakes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0686.JPG" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before getting back to camp. I decided that it would be a good idea to move my camp to the pass itself, so I packed up and moved my camp about 1/4 mile to the north and then went through the pass to look at 1,000 Island Lake on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0689.JPG" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, as you can probably tell, the weather had taken a turn for the worse, and so I headed back to camp to button up for the night. The fog got really thick and the water loosened the rocks on the mountains, which I could hear tumbling down the mountainsides all night long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0695.JPG" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I found out that my bivy sack was not waterproof, and by the time the night was over, I was sleeping in a puddle of water. It was the most miserable night I have ever slept through in the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Failed Attempt on Mt Ritter - The Approach</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the summer of 2014, after I had been working at Summit Adventure in Bass Lake, California, I set off to climb Mt. Ritter by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day I drove up to the trailhead and then hiked up the trail until it was dark before setting&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/failed-attempt-on-mt-ritter-the-approach/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3bf28eb850b00e1e8d3049</guid><category>Mt. Ritter</category><category>2014</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 02:26:58 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0670.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0670.JPG" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt Ritter - The Approach"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the summer of 2014, after I had been working at Summit Adventure in Bass Lake, California, I set off to climb Mt. Ritter by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day I drove up to the trailhead and then hiked up the trail until it was dark before setting up camp. In the morning I woke up to this, with the beautiful sunrise caused by all of the wildfires in the area,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0672.JPG" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt Ritter - The Approach"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then began hiking again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went down one side of the North Fork of the San Joaquin River canyon, crossed the river at Hemlock Crossing. I continued up the North Fork until I need to head to the right up to Glacier Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my way, I met a troop of boy scouts heading up and a couple heading down the pass. I made it all of the ways up to Lake Marie before heading south and setting up camp next to one of the Ritter Lakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/failed-attemp-on-mt-ritter-the-climb/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I had gotten lost on Day 2, most of day three was spend retracing my steps and getting back on the right path. I woke up, had my breakfast, tried to go a little farther up the canyon before realizing that I had made the complete wrong turn at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-3-back-on-track/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3b977d9acf680a8a4a11ed</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:00:26 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081146.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081146.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I had gotten lost on Day 2, most of day three was spend retracing my steps and getting back on the right path. I woke up, had my breakfast, tried to go a little farther up the canyon before realizing that I had made the complete wrong turn at the bridge and headed back down the canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I crossed the bridge at about noon or so and began hiking up the correct canyon, stopping for lunch in an area with burned out trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I passed the trail intersection that comes from the Wind River Reservation, where an outfitter had set up a tent and had several horses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I passed many beautiful meadows and was able to see the Gannet Peak for the very first time of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081154.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hiked until it was dark, having passed one older couple with external frame backpacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-2-wrong-turn/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, it was overcast and grey and just barely drizzling. Fortunately, unlike some of my other adventures, I had stayed dry throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up, retrieved my food from its bear hang, packed my stuff and headed down the trail. I passed several lakes and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-2-wrong-turn/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3b931f9acf680a8a4a11eb</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:37:55 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8070774.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8070774.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, it was overcast and grey and just barely drizzling. Fortunately, unlike some of my other adventures, I had stayed dry throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up, retrieved my food from its bear hang, packed my stuff and headed down the trail. I passed several lakes and by midmorning the sky had cleared and it finally warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I descended all of the way into the canyon which was less than fun due to all of the weight I was carrying. It was a long ways down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8070888.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the bridge that was supposed to be damaged and then I made a mistake. Instead of crossing the bridge, I continued on past up the canyon. It was rough going and eventually the trail simply gave out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8071011.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-3-back-on-track/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-1-beginning/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Triple Divide Peak</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2014, I set out to climb Triple Divide peak in the Ansel Adam's wilderness in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I parked at the Balls and headed up towards Jackass Lake. From Jackass Lake I went straight north, going down the ridge to the trail. Following the trail up and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/triple-divide-peak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c36c52dc431d6083f1d3fc9</guid><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 04:21:27 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/tripledivide--copy--1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/tripledivide--copy--1.jpg" alt="Triple Divide Peak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2014, I set out to climb Triple Divide peak in the Ansel Adam's wilderness in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I parked at the Balls and headed up towards Jackass Lake. From Jackass Lake I went straight north, going down the ridge to the trail. Following the trail up and around to the west I passed many lakes and other peaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last bit of the trail up to the lakes just below the peak was overgrown and hard to follow but I finally made it and camped up on the ridge to the north east of the lake after setting down my backpack and then nearly losing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few mosquitoes and it was overcast and kept looking like it was going to storm but it never did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up early the next morning and finished the approach before climbing the peak from the southeast gully. At the top was a marker from the turn of the century and a grand view in all directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was spent hiking all of the way out and included some interesting bushwacking due to the shortcuts I took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got of work early on a Friday and packed my stuff before driving most of the way to the trailhead. I got sleepy, so I pulled over and slept in the back of my truck just before reaching Lander, Wyoming. In the morning I headed out and got to&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-1-beginning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c36c0aac431d6083f1d3fc5</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 03:58:51 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060122.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060122.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got of work early on a Friday and packed my stuff before driving most of the way to the trailhead. I got sleepy, so I pulled over and slept in the back of my truck just before reaching Lander, Wyoming. In the morning I headed out and got to the trailhead around 8:30 or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began to finish organizing my gear and packing my backpack. In stuffing my sleeping bag into the very bottom, I ripped  one of my fingernails up and nearly off and had to wrap it with some athletic tape to protect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the trailhead, there was a warning that one of the bridges had been damaged and that crossing was at your own risk. The trail starts out moderately steep in a very hot high desert sort of feel to the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060002.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It stays along the stream and then you begin going up a steep hill with many switchbacks. The switchbacks continue until you reach the tree line and then the trail becomes much less steep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the treeline one must go up and then back down and while it was not very steep, it sure seemed to go on for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060508.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reaching the top of the pass, I descended down the other side until I reached the treeline again and then I setup camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-2-wrong-turn/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Keyhole Route On Long's Peak</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This summer I climbed Long's Peak in Colorad via the Keyhole route. It was a peak that I have often seen and wanted to climb before the summer was over and conditions became unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out from the trailhead at midnight on a Saturday and began walking up the&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/keyhole-route-on-longs-peak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5bdf3d632f0e840bec2e7141</guid><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 19:13:14 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/IMG_0457.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/IMG_0457.png" alt="Keyhole Route On Long's Peak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This summer I climbed Long's Peak in Colorad via the Keyhole route. It was a peak that I have often seen and wanted to climb before the summer was over and conditions became unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out from the trailhead at midnight on a Saturday and began walking up the hill. I passed on other hiker right away and met a party of four coming down the hill which seemed unusual due to it being 1:00 am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to tell how far you have gone in the dark, each step seems to look very much like the next, especially in a wooded area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the second trail intersection I found a pair of abandoned waterproof pants and at the third I stopped and talked with two other hikers and watched some shooting stars go by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I could finally sort of tell where I was, and once I reached the campground right below the Keyhole I stopped and filled up on water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point on the trail ends and the scrambling begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still dark when I passed through the Keyhole and began following the ledges up across the side of the mountain. In the darkness it was impossible to tell the exposure, there was just blackness down below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once past the ledges, it was a number of switchbacks up the Trough and then some short rockclimbing moves to move out of the Trough and onto the narrows. This was the one section where I really could have used better boots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you must cross the Narrows and then up the Homestretch. While the Narrows has greater exposure, it was easier than the Ledges since the sun was beginning to dawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Homestrech was pretty easy climbing, some hikers did turn around at this point due to the lightning in the far distance, but that was a long ways off in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I reached the top,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/11/IMG_0465.png" alt="Keyhole Route On Long's Peak"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stayed for 15-20 minutes to take pictures and then headed down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting down was fairly miserable, I had a headache and nausea from the altitude and the weather turned nasty once I was through the Kyehole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going down the Trough someone knocked two basketball sized rocks loose and they flew down the gully past 20-30 people, it would have not been good if the rocks had hit someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a marmot that wanted my lunch when I sat down to rest, but other than that the hike out was uneventful, if long and tiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got back to my vehicle and slept for several hours before heading out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Panoramas from Elk Hunting above the North Platte River</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last weekend I was elk hunting up above the North Platte River in Wyoming and captured these two panoramas,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking away from the river,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/11/ckBMv-1.jpg" alt="ckBMv-1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking down to the river and towards the Sierra Madres in the far distance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/11/Dpzsb.png" alt="Dpzsb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were plenty of deer and bighorn sheep but no elk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/panoramas-from-elk-hunting/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5bdf36dd2f0e840bec2e7140</guid><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 18:17:38 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last weekend I was elk hunting up above the North Platte River in Wyoming and captured these two panoramas,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking away from the river,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/11/ckBMv-1.jpg" alt="ckBMv-1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking down to the river and towards the Sierra Madres in the far distance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/11/Dpzsb.png" alt="Dpzsb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were plenty of deer and bighorn sheep but no elk to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Visiting Bryce Canyon National Park</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After doing &lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/climbing-copper-belt-peak/"&gt;Copper Belt Peak&lt;/a&gt;, I headed south to Bryce Canyon, again sleeping in my car and then heading into the park in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode the shuttle bus in and went as far out as it would take me, then did a hike down one part of the&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/visiting-bryce-canyon-national-park/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b57f1d982c67e0b4f771224</guid><category>2017 Adventure</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 03:50:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After doing &lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/climbing-copper-belt-peak/"&gt;Copper Belt Peak&lt;/a&gt;, I headed south to Bryce Canyon, again sleeping in my car and then heading into the park in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode the shuttle bus in and went as far out as it would take me, then did a hike down one part of the canyon and back up the other side. While it was really cool scenery, the descent was hard and my feet were still hurting from the Copper Belt Ascent, plus the trails were as hard as concrete. Once I was done with the hike, I sat in the shade for a while, and then took the shuttle back out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a pullout to camp on just outside the park, and then got up at about 1:00 in the morning, and from there I hiked into the park, to see the stars and the sunrise. The moon was barely out and the stars were brilliant. There were a few other people in the park taking pictures of the stars, and the odd headlamp in the distance, but other than that it was totally quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before sunrise, I made my way to Sunset point and set up my camera to take a timelapse of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the sunrise and talked with an older gentlemen about photography and his adventures riding a motorcycle across the United States when he was young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I walked back out to take a nap next to my truck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Failed summit attempt on Laramie Peak</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in college,5 of us decided that we were going to attempt to climb Laramie Peak. It's not a huge peak, but it is very prominent, and very easy to see for a really long ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the others had a school function and so we&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/failed-summit-attempt-on-laramie-peak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b57f31682c67e0b4f771226</guid><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 04:15:44 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in college,5 of us decided that we were going to attempt to climb Laramie Peak. It's not a huge peak, but it is very prominent, and very easy to see for a really long ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the others had a school function and so we did not get started driving until around midnight. It was proably an hour and a half drive, and it turned out that the directions I had did not account for a road being closed. Eventually we gave up trying to find it in the dark and slept in the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we woke up, we had an awesome view of the peak which had a large lenticular cloud streaming past the summit. We decided to attempt to climb it from the east side, starting out at a Boy Scout camp and then just heading up (the trail was on the other side of the mountain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we had a small mountain to climb with a firewatching tower on top, where we stopped and had lunch. Then we went back down that mountain, finding a large bull snake about halfway down, before finally heading up Laramie Peak. We stuck to the top of the easternmost ridge, weaving our way up around various dead logs and rock outcroppings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we decide that if we were not at the top by 5:30 pm we would have to turn around regardless. When 5:30 pm came, we were within a mile and 1,000 vertical feet of the top, but it was starting to snow and we headed back down the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About half a mile from the saddle between Laramie Peak and the little mountain, I turned around and looked back up and there was a blanket of fog heading down the mountain towards us. Very shortly there was a blanket of fog coming down the small mountain ahead of us as well. We reached the saddle just as it got dark, and the fog reached us about the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the night is a blur of hiking in the dark, dehydrated, out of food and crossing rock slabs of uncertain height.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually made it all the way back to the vehicle and from there back to school. It was one heck of an epic adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Climbing Copper Belt Peak</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After leaving Salt Lake City, I headed south, stopping around Spanish Fork to go hiking for a day and then continuing until I reached Marysvale, where I saw some mountains that looked like they were worth climbing, and headed east up a dirt road getting to a campsite in a&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/climbing-copper-belt-peak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b300ce43bad1d133e1f3f0c</guid><category>2017 Adventure</category><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 03:41:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After leaving Salt Lake City, I headed south, stopping around Spanish Fork to go hiking for a day and then continuing until I reached Marysvale, where I saw some mountains that looked like they were worth climbing, and headed east up a dirt road getting to a campsite in a canyon just before dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning I woke and packed a light daypack and headed up the south side of the canyon, scrambling up small boulders and the winding my around until I was out of the canyon, onto the west side of the mountain range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started it was all sagebrush and juniper, as I got higher up, it turned to spruce and aspen on the north side of the ridge, while the south facing side was completely bare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw probably 20-30 mountain goats and passed quite a number of trees that had been initialed by sheepherders back in the early 1920-30 which I found rather interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I got out of the trees completely and got to the final leg of the climb where I had to kick steps in the snow in order to ascend. Upon reaching the top, I sent a message with my inReach and took a number of photographs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way off the peak I was able to glissade for a little bit, and then it was back to slogging through the brush all over again. Instead of going the long way back, I descended directly into the canyon to the south, in order to walk back on the road that went through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw several grouse on the way down and then old mining cabins and tailings on my hike down the road back to my vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>2017 Summer Adventure Begins</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the summer of 2017 I quit my job and headed out on a four month trip to backpack and hike climb mountains in the western United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get out and do some big adventures and this seemed like an awesome way to do&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2017-summer-adventure-begins/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b300141b2b1a50e87b41f02</guid><category>2017 Adventure</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:44:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the summer of 2017 I quit my job and headed out on a four month trip to backpack and hike climb mountains in the western United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get out and do some big adventures and this seemed like an awesome way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start with, I began in Cheyenne, stocking up on food in Laramie and then driving across Wyoming to Salt Lake city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there I stopped at a park to see and old friend and we hung out and talked for quite a while, not having seen the other in over a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I drove south and ended up sleeping in my car in an empty parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Basic Black and White Algorithms</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of different ways of converting a color image to Black and White, but, once you understand the basic idea, it gets simpler from there. The short version is that in a color image, there are different RGB (Red,Green,Blue) values for each pixel, while in a&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/basic-black-and-white/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b2ffd5ab2b1a50e87b41eff</guid><category>Programming</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 20:22:13 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/3ESlt.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/3ESlt.jpg" alt="Basic Black and White Algorithms"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of different ways of converting a color image to Black and White, but, once you understand the basic idea, it gets simpler from there. The short version is that in a color image, there are different RGB (Red,Green,Blue) values for each pixel, while in a B&amp;amp;W image the RGB values for each pixel are the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the RGB values for a pixel in a color image might be 200,100,50 and if one was to convert it to a red channel B&amp;amp;W, you would set the values of the pixel to 200,200,200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the simpler B&amp;amp;W algorithms include,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red channel -&amp;gt; Set the blue and green pixels to match the red pixels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue channel -&amp;gt; Set the red and green pixels to match the blue pixels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green channel -&amp;gt; Set the blue and red pixels to match the green pixels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maximum -&amp;gt; Set the values of the pixel to match the largest value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum -&amp;gt; Set the values of the pixel to match the smallest value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>