<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Charlie Brumbaugh's Blog</title><description>Outdoor Adventures and Programming</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Charlie Brumbaugh's Blog</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 2.11</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 04:28:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 8 - Visiting the Bomber Wreck</title><description>The last day of the the trip I hiked to the wreck of a B-24 that had crashed while on a training mission during the Second World War.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-8-visiting-the-bomber-wreck/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4e82f4a28b4607dcc832e5</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 04:21:42 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8133755-1.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8133755-1.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 8 - Visiting the Bomber Wreck"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last day of the the trip I hiked to the wreck of a B-24 that had crashed while on a training mission during the Second World War.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trail was broken in places and I had to cross a marsh and then go through a thick patch of woods before I reached it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was aluminum scatted all over and it was possible to see where the fire from the crash had melted it into pools. All of the engines were still there, though some of the propellers had been cut off, while one could see how the trees had grown up since then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8133732.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 8 - Visiting the Bomber Wreck"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I hiked back to camp and from there back to the trailhead and then home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-7-over-the-top/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 7 - Over the Top</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I woke up in no hurry and began the hike up the hill, having first looked for tipi rings, and taking more photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the crest of the hill,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8123304.JPG" class="kg-image"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was passed by two hikers trailing a llama each. They carried no gear, except the pistol one had, and moved&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-7-over-the-top/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4e8287a28b4607dcc832da</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 04:19:36 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8123292-1.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8123292-1.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 7 - Over the Top"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I woke up in no hurry and began the hike up the hill, having first looked for tipi rings, and taking more photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the crest of the hill,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8123304.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 7 - Over the Top"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was passed by two hikers trailing a llama each. They carried no gear, except the pistol one had, and moved a lot faster than me. It seemed like the way to travel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just before treeline, I passed two parties, the first making noise with their bear bells and carrying bear spray, while the in the second, they all had large revolvers. It was quite an interesting contrast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made it back down the switchbacks and then turned left up the canyon because I wanted to see the B-24 wreck the next day. I got in early, so there was plenty of time to think and I picked some berries and spent some time next to the river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8123617.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 7 - Over the Top"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-8-visiting-the-bomber-wreck/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-6-out-of-the-canyon/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 6 - Out of the Canyon</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On the morning of day 6, I woke up early, packed my gear and headed down the trail without breakfast, because I wanted to get out ahead of the snowmelt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The stream was still high, but it had gone down during the night enough that I could cross it on&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-6-out-of-the-canyon/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4e8201a28b4607dcc832cc</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 04:17:28 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8113232.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8113232.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 6 - Out of the Canyon"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the morning of day 6, I woke up early, packed my gear and headed down the trail without breakfast, because I wanted to get out ahead of the snowmelt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The stream was still high, but it had gone down during the night enough that I could cross it on several logs and was low enough for all of the rest of the crossings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once past the crossings I stopped and had breakfast, and took some pictures of Gannet Peak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8112899.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 6 - Out of the Canyon"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I headed further down the trail with a few showers but no major events. I recrossed the bridge that was said to have been damaged and had lunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8113250.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 6 - Out of the Canyon"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made it all of the way back out of the canyon, back to where &lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-1-beginning/"&gt;I camped on my first night out&lt;/a&gt;. Overall it was a really long day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8113261.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 6 - Out of the Canyon"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-7-over-the-top/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-5-the-ascent/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 5 - The Ascent</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I started out from camp twice, the first time I woke up at 1:00 am, loaded my stuff in the dark and headed into the boulder field. It was dark and before I got very far it started sleeting and there were no stars to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-5-the-ascent/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4e810ea28b4607dcc832b7</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 04:14:51 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8102436-1.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8102436-1.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 5 - The Ascent"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started out from camp twice, the first time I woke up at 1:00 am, loaded my stuff in the dark and headed into the boulder field. It was dark and before I got very far it started sleeting and there were no stars to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided the extra risk of slipping wasn't worth it, so I went back through the boulder field to camp and got back into my sleeping bag. At approximately 4:00 am, I was awoken by a party of three starting out and the older couple getting ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I looked up, the stars were out so I decided that it was a go. I hurriedly reorganized my stuff and headed back up through the boulder field. I reached the snow just as it was getting light and put my mountaineering boots and crampons on. There was some hard ice and more snow, before another section of rock to reach the Gooseneck Glacier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8102413.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 5 - The Ascent"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The traverse over to the bergschrund was pretty level and there was even a path worn into the snow from the previous climbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8102422.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 5 - The Ascent"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the actual bergschrund crossing was kinda hairy, because there were two major cracks, mandating that one go up, then traverse to the left above the crack, go up again, then traverse right back over the top of the first crack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once I was at the top of the chute, the snow ran out and I stashed my crampons. From there it was a pretty straight forward climb up the ridge to the summit, with no major hurdles and plenty of wide ledges to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once at the summit I found the summit register and stopped to take photos. I could see all of the ways to the Tetons, while to the south the mountain peaks stretched into the far distance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8102436.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 5 - The Ascent"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started the descent, passing the party of three who had awoken me in the morning and was able to get enough of a cell signal to text my parents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going down the ridge was pretty easy, getting down to the Gooseneck chute was not. Once at the chute, I put my crampons back on, and backed down the bergschrund, firmly planting my ice ax with both hands before moving my feet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The snow was a lot more melted than when I came up, and while going down the bergschrund I crossed paths with the two gentlemen from the day before, as well as the older couple down below while traversing across the glacier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8102823.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 5 - The Ascent"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once back on the glacier it was just a slow process of going down the rocks and boulders and scree. I finally got back to my camp and took a nap to rest. When I go up, I decided that I wanted to be below timberline in case it rained, so I packed up my gear and headed down the trail. Just before the timberline, I got caught in a small hailstorm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made it all the way back until the major stream crossing, and the snow melt had raised the water level to an uncross-able degree, so I set up camp and waited till the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-6-out-of-the-canyon/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-4-getting-to-base-camp/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 4 - Getting to Base Camp</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On Day 4 I woke up, had breakfast and began heading up the trail once more. I had one serious creek crossing that made me glad that I had gotten up early and not waited till the snow melt made it much worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finally got above the treeline, and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-4-getting-to-base-camp/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c4e7fb9a28b4607dcc832a2</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 04:10:13 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8091507.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8091507.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 4 - Getting to Base Camp"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Day 4 I woke up, had breakfast and began heading up the trail once more. I had one serious creek crossing that made me glad that I had gotten up early and not waited till the snow melt made it much worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finally got above the treeline, and continued up the wide glacial valley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8091491.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 4 - Getting to Base Camp"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wasn't too much longer that I turned the corner and was able to see the peaks at the end of the glacially carved valley and the Gooseneck glacier. I hiked all of the way to the end of the trail and set up camp in one of the rock rings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next I took just a daypack and went forward through the boulderfields until I came to one of the small tarns, in order to get a better view of what I would need to climb the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would need to make my way to the base of the Gooseneck, cross the bergschrund and then follow the ridge to the right all the way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8091627.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 4 - Getting to Base Camp"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point I took a nap, then had a conversation with two other climbers about the route and weather. Later on that day the couple that I had passed the day before arrived and setup camp in one of the nearby rock rings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8092285.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 4 - Getting to Base Camp"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took several time lapses, organized my gear, ate well and discovered a bronze plague below the camp where a pioneer's ashes had been scattered. Then I crawled into by sleeping bag and tried to get some sleep for the summit attempt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-5-the-ascent/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://charliebrumbaugh.github.io/gannet-peak-day-3-back-on-track/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Since I had gotten lost on Day 2, most of day three was spend retracing my steps and getting back on the right path. I woke up, had my breakfast, tried to go a little farther up the canyon before realizing that I had made the complete wrong turn at&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-3-back-on-track/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fed646045d00e5b18e2fa</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:51:18 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081146.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081146.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I had gotten lost on Day 2, most of day three was spend retracing my steps and getting back on the right path. I woke up, had my breakfast, tried to go a little farther up the canyon before realizing that I had made the complete wrong turn at the bridge and headed back down the canyon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I crossed the bridge at about noon or so and began hiking up the correct canyon, stopping for lunch in an area with burned out trees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081034.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I passed the trail intersection that comes from the Wind River Reservation, where an outfitter had set up a tent and had several horses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I passed many beautiful meadows and was able to see the Gannet Peak for the very first time of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8081154.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 3 - Back on Track"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hiked until it was dark, having passed one older couple with external frame backpacks, one single man who was thinking about turning around and a father and son team who did turn around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got to camp and after I was all set up with my tarp, I was startled by a single cow elk that wandered through. I took several time lapses with my camera, and then went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, it was overcast and grey and just barely drizzling. Fortunately, unlike some of my other adventures, I had stayed dry throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got up, retrieved my food from its bear hang, packed my stuff and headed down the trail. I passed several lakes and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-2-wrong-turn/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fec906045d00e5b18e2ec</guid><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:49:17 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8070774.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8070774.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, it was overcast and grey and just barely drizzling. Fortunately, unlike some of my other adventures, I had stayed dry throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got up, retrieved my food from its bear hang, packed my stuff and headed down the trail. I passed several lakes and by midmorning the sky had cleared and it finally warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I descended all of the way into the canyon which was less than fun due to all of the weight I was carrying. It was a long ways down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8070888.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found the bridge that was supposed to be damaged and &lt;strong&gt;then I made a mistake. Instead of crossing the bridge, I continued on past up the canyon&lt;/strong&gt;. It was rough going and eventually the trail simply gave out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8071011.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 2 - Wrong Turn"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, I still thought that I was on the right path, so I continued up the canyon, following the stream. Eventually, it got dark and at a seemingly dead end, so I set up camp underneath of a rock, with my tarp stretched out at a 45 degree angle to keep the rain off.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning</title><description>In the summer of 2016 I decided that I wanted to climb Gannet Peak, the highest point in Wyoming and the most remote of all of the state high points.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/gannet-peak-day-1-beginning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3febd06045d00e5b18e2db</guid><category>Gannet Peak</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:46:22 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060122.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060122.JPG" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2016 I decided that I wanted to climb Gannet Peak, the highest point in Wyoming and the most remote of all of the state high points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got of work early on a Friday and packed my stuff before driving most of the way to the trailhead. I got sleepy, so I pulled over and slept in the back of my truck just before reaching Lander, Wyoming. In the morning I headed out and got to the trail head around 8:30 or so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I began to finish organizing my gear and packing my backpack. In stuffing my sleeping bag into the very bottom, I ripped one of my fingernails up and nearly off and had to wrap it with some athletic tape to protect it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the trailhead, there was a warning that one of the bridges had been damaged and that crossing was at your own risk. The trail starts out moderately steep in a very hot high desert sort of feel to the place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060002.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;It stays along the stream and then you begin going up a steep hill with many switchbacks. The switchbacks continue until you reach the tree line and then the trail becomes much less steep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the treeline one must go up and then back down and while it was not very steep, it sure seemed to go on for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P8060508.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Gannet Peak - Day 1 - Beginning"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;After reaching the top of the hill, I descended down the other side until I reached the treeline again and then I setup camp.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Failed Attempt on Mt. Ritter - Walkout</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I woke up and headed out just as fast as I could, the soaking wet sleeping bag meant that I was less miserable once I was hiking out. I started before the sunrise but only had to use my headlight for a short while before it grew light enough to&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/failed-attempt-on-mt-ritter-walkout/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe8ed6045d00e5b18e2ca</guid><category>Mt. Ritter</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:33:38 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0696.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0696.JPG" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt. Ritter - Walkout"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I woke up and headed out just as fast as I could, the soaking wet sleeping bag meant that I was less miserable once I was hiking out. I started before the sunrise but only had to use my headlight for a short while before it grew light enough to do without.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walking back down Glacier Pass was an adventure, especially since the fog followed me down, making it impossible to see where I had been. The slickness of the rocks also made the going much slower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0697.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt. Ritter - Walkout"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continued on down, passing  two lakes,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0698.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt. Ritter - Walkout"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;and heading on down the canyon. I paused to take this picture of Mt. Ritter and then kept on hiking. Once at the bottom of the canyon, one could see that the weather had gotten much worse,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0715.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt. Ritter - Walkout"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;and it was a dreary hike back down to Hemlock Crossing. I thought about camping there for the night, but my wet sleeping bag persuaded me otherwise. So I began the long hike up and out of the canyon, with all of the many switchbacks that entailed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I passed two hikers heading down, and picked up a discarded long sleeve t-shirt that someone had hung in a tree along the trail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I stopped for dinner once I was completely out of the canyon and took a moment to appreciate the beauty and how far I had come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0720.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt. Ritter - Walkout"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point my sleeping bag was still soaked, so I hiked all of the ways back to the trailhead, and slept in the back of my truck, then drove back to Summit Adventure the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/failed-attemp-on-mt-ritter-the-climb/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The day of the climb, I woke up really early and headed up the mountain. It was hard going with lots of talus and rubble. I made it up to the final lake and then headed straight up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At some point, I missed the right-hand turn to the second bowl&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/failed-attemp-on-mt-ritter-the-climb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe7e86045d00e5b18e2bc</guid><category>Mt. Ritter</category><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:29:51 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0691.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0691.JPG" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day of the climb, I woke up really early and headed up the mountain. It was hard going with lots of talus and rubble. I made it up to the final lake and then headed straight up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At some point, I missed the right-hand turn to the second bowl and headed straight on pass it. It turned out that the rocks were too steep and after I knocked a basketball sized rock loose and it rolled and rolled and rolled, I decided to take some pictures and head down. It was only 7:03 in the morning when I decided to quit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0678.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I headed back down the mountain, pausing to take this picture of the Ritter Lakes,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0686.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;before getting back to camp. I decided that it would be a good idea to move my camp to the pass itself, so I packed up and moved my camp about 1/4 mile to the north and then went through the pass to look at 1,000 Island Lake on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0692.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, as you can probably tell, the weather had taken a turn for the worse, and so I headed back to camp to button up for the night. The fog got really thick and the water loosened the rocks on the mountains, which I could hear tumbling down the mountainsides all night long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0695.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attemp on Mt. Ritter - The Climb"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, I found out that my bivy sack was not waterproof, and by the time the night was over, I was sleeping in a puddle of water. It was the most miserable night I have ever slept through in the outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/failed-attempt-on-mt-ritter-walkout/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/failed-attempt-on-mt-ritter-the-approach/"&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Failed Attempt on Mt Ritter - The Approach</title><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of the summer of 2014, after I had been working at Summit Adventure in Bass Lake, California, I set off to climb Mt. Ritter by myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first day I drove up to the trailhead and then hiked up the trail until it was dark before setting&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/failed-attempt-on-mt-ritter-the-approach/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe7026045d00e5b18e2b2</guid><category>Mt. Ritter</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:25:32 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0670-1.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0670-1.JPG" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt Ritter - The Approach"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the summer of 2014, after I had been working at Summit Adventure in Bass Lake, California, I set off to climb Mt. Ritter by myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first day I drove up to the trailhead and then hiked up the trail until it was dark before setting up camp. In the morning I woke up to this, with the beautiful sunrise caused by all of the wildfires in the area,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/DSCN0672.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Failed Attempt on Mt Ritter - The Approach"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;and then began hiking again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went down one side of the North Fork of the San Joaquin River canyon, crossed the river at Hemlock Crossing. I continued up the North Fork until I need to head to the right up to Glacier Pass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my way, I met a troop of boy scouts heading up and a couple heading down the pass. I made it all of the ways up to Lake Marie before heading south and setting up camp next to one of the Ritter Lakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/failed-attemp-on-mt-ritter-the-climb/"&gt;Continued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Triple Divide Peak</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2014, I set out to climb Triple Divide peak in the Ansel Adam's wilderness in California.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I parked at the Balls and headed up towards Jackass Lake. From Jackass Lake I went straight north, going down the ridge to the trail. Following the trail up and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/triple-divide-peak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe6276045d00e5b18e2ad</guid><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:19:55 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/tripledivide--copy-.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/tripledivide--copy-.jpg" alt="Triple Divide Peak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2014, I set out to climb Triple Divide peak in the Ansel Adam's wilderness in California.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I parked at the Balls and headed up towards Jackass Lake. From Jackass Lake I went straight north, going down the ridge to the trail. Following the trail up and around to the west I passed many lakes and other peaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last bit of the trail up to the lakes just below the peak was overgrown and hard to follow but I finally made it and camped up on the ridge to the north east of the lake after setting down my backpack and then nearly losing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a few mosquitoes and it was overcast and kept looking like it was going to storm but it never did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got up early the next morning and finished the approach before climbing the peak from the southeast gully. At the top was a marker from the turn of the century and a grand view in all directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was spent hiking all of the way out and included some interesting bushwacking due to the shortcuts I took.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Mammoth Cave Utah</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mammoth_Cave_(Utah)"&gt;Mammoth Cave in Utah&lt;/a&gt; is a very interesting place. The short version is that it is comprised of two intersecting lava tubes that form a rough X. It collapsed almost at the dead center of the X and that is how one accesses it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5136118.JPG" class="kg-image"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are four chambers with one&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/mammoth-cave-utah/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe53e6045d00e5b18e2a1</guid><category>2017 Adventure</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:17:56 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/aWN8r.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/aWN8r.jpg" alt="Mammoth Cave Utah"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mammoth_Cave_(Utah)"&gt;Mammoth Cave in Utah&lt;/a&gt; is a very interesting place. The short version is that it is comprised of two intersecting lava tubes that form a rough X. It collapsed almost at the dead center of the X and that is how one accesses it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5136118.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Mammoth Cave Utah"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are four chambers with one having a metal grill to keep people out during certain parts of the year in order to protect the bats that live there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5136122.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Mammoth Cave Utah"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of bats, once I was a good ways into the south cave, there were at least a hundred bats in the ceiling crevices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5136116.JPG" class="kg-image" alt="Mammoth Cave Utah"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bat's made quite a din of squeaking, and once I had explored all of the caves, I had my dinner above aground, took some pictures and waited for the bats to come out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They never came out, I think it was just too cold for them. Once it got dark enough to need a headlight, I walked back to my truck and cooked my dinner over a campfire.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Keyhole Route On Long's Peak</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This summer I climbed Long's Peak in Colorad via the Keyhole route. It was a peak that I have often seen and wanted to climb before the summer was over and conditions became unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started out from the trailhead at midnight on a Saturday and began walking up the&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/keyhole-route-on-longs-peak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe3fc6045d00e5b18e298</guid><category>Peak Ascents</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:11:22 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/IMG_0457-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/IMG_0457-1.png" alt="Keyhole Route On Long's Peak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This summer I climbed Long's Peak in Colorad via the Keyhole route. It was a peak that I have often seen and wanted to climb before the summer was over and conditions became unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started out from the trailhead at midnight on a Saturday and began walking up the hill. I passed on other hiker right away and met a party of four coming down the hill which seemed unusual due to it being 1:00 am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's hard to tell how far you have gone in the dark, each step seems to look very much like the next, especially in a wooded area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the second trail intersection I found a pair of abandoned waterproof pants and at the third I stopped and talked with two other hikers and watched some shooting stars go by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point I could finally sort of tell where I was, and once I reached the campground right below the Keyhole I stopped and filled up on water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From this point on the trail ends and the scrambling begins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was still dark when I passed through the Keyhole and began following the ledges up across the side of the mountain. In the darkness it was impossible to tell the exposure, there was just blackness down below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once past the ledges, it was a number of switchbacks up the Trough and then some short rockclimbing moves to move out of the Trough and onto the narrows. This was the one section where I really could have used better boots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then you must cross the Narrows and then up the Homestretch. While the Narrows has greater exposure, it was easier than the Ledges since the sun was beginning to dawn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Homestrech was pretty easy climbing, some hikers did turn around at this point due to the lightning in the far distance, but that was a long ways off in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally I reached the top,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/IMG_0457.png" class="kg-image" alt="Keyhole Route On Long's Peak"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;stayed for 15-20 minutes to take pictures and then headed down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting down was fairly miserable, I had a headache and nausea from the altitude and the weather turned nasty once I was through the Kyehole. Going down the Trough someone knocked two basketball sized rocks loose and they flew down the gully past 20-30 people, it would have not been good if the rocks had hit someone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a marmot that wanted my lunch when I sat down to rest, but other than that the hike out was uneventful, if long and tiring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got back to my vehicle and slept for several hours before heading out.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Visiting Bryce Canyon National Park</title><description>&lt;p&gt;After doing &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/climbing-copper-belt-peak/"&gt;Copper Belt Peak&lt;/a&gt;, I headed south to Bryce Canyon, again sleeping in my car and then heading into the park in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode the shuttle bus in and went as far out as it would take me, then did a hike down one part of the&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/visiting-bryce-canyon-national-park/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3fe2856045d00e5b18e281</guid><category>2017 Adventure</category><dc:creator>Charlie Brumbaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:04:54 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5034991.JPG" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5034991.JPG" alt="Visiting Bryce Canyon National Park"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After doing &lt;a href="http://localhost:2368/climbing-copper-belt-peak/"&gt;Copper Belt Peak&lt;/a&gt;, I headed south to Bryce Canyon, again sleeping in my car and then heading into the park in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rode the shuttle bus in and went as far out as it would take me, then did a hike down one part of the canyon and back up the other side. While it was really cool scenery, the descent was hard and my feet were still hurting from the Copper Belt Ascent, plus the trails were as hard as concrete. Once I was done with the hike, I sat in the shade for a while, and then took the shuttle back out.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/P5034888.JPG" alt="Visiting Bryce Canyon National Park"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I found a pullout to camp on just outside the park, and then got up at about 1:00 in the morning, and from there I hiked into the park, to see the stars and the sunrise. The moon was barely out and the stars were brilliant. There were a few other people in the park taking pictures of the stars, and the odd headlamp in the distance, but other than that it was totally quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before sunrise, I made my way to Sunset point and set up my camera to take a timelapse of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the sunrise and talked with an older gentlemen about photography and his adventures riding a motorcycle across the United States when he was young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I walked back out to take a nap next to my truck.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>